<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Project | frogplague]]></title>
  <link href="http://thoughts.frogplague.com/blog/categories/project/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://thoughts.frogplague.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-08T07:51:09-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://thoughts.frogplague.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Devon Tackett]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[frogplague@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Indirect Journey]]></title>
    <link href="http://thoughts.frogplague.com/blog/2014/05/08/an-indirect-journey/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-08T07:48:41-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://thoughts.frogplague.com/blog/2014/05/08/an-indirect-journey</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Several months ago I had the notion that I should expand my horizons and learn a bit of Javascript. <!-- more --> I have quite a few years of experience with Java so the basic language constructs did not seem alien. There were a few key differences here and there but nothing so wild as to make it inaccessible.</p>

<p>After a few building a few toy examples I decided it was time to try something larger. Rather than doing something reasonable like building an application I might encounter in my day to day work I chose to go back to why I started programming in the first place. I decided to take a go at making a game.</p>

<p>Now I have a long and distinguished history of starting side game projects and never completing them. Something always comes up in life or I get away from it too long and jump down some other rabbit hole. In this latest effort I must admit that I haven&rsquo;t been the most consistent. However I have managed to keep dabbling on again and off again for several months.</p>

<p>Shortly after I started toying with a project I became enamored with the idea of functional programming. Now it is entirely possible to do functional programming in Javascript. There is even an <a href="http://funjs.herokuapp.com/">excellent book</a> on the matter. However since Clojure is what caught my eye I jumped straight into ClojureScript.</p>

<p>Now I don&rsquo;t have much of a game to show at this moment. The basics of a 2d platformed are there. It isn&rsquo;t exciting or novel in any way but I have made progress. I decided to follow a <a href="http://www.chris-granger.com/2012/12/11/anatomy-of-a-knockout/">Component Entity System</a> and I&rsquo;ve been enjoying it. I know there are several Component Entity Systems out there. Even a few of them are in Clojure. In my defense I could not find a Clojure based solution when I first started. Granted there are some out now that are certainly more complete than what I have written. Even if my solution will not be used (or even seen) by anyone else I am getting value out of building it for myself. My end goal wasn&rsquo;t so much to make the game as much as it was to gain some experience in building a functional project. Quite the departure from where I originally started.</p>

<p>I have broken down my work into the game itself <a href="http://github.com/dtackett/sivinolk">Sivinolk</a>, my Component Entity System <a href="http://github.com/dtackett/vyrlynd">Vyrlynd</a> and a crude input library <a href="http://github.com/dtackett/clinp">Clinp</a>. I intend to reflect a bit on my tilts at the windmills on these efforts in the future. For now it seems worth noting that they exist.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
